NAJMUDDIN AMDAN

BACKEND DEVELOPER

muhammadnajmuddin1907@gmail.com

+601110944393

Cheras, Kuala Lumpur

Profile Summary

Junior software engineer with one year of web application development experience. Adept at creating databases, APIs, and user-centered experiences. Possesses extensive training in frameworks, software development, systems design, and application optimization.

Professional Skill

- Golang Laravel PHP HTML JAVA C++ AWS S3 Docker
- MongoDB PostgreSQL MySQL JavaScript GitHub GitLab Postman AWS Lambda

Education

Diploma in Computer Science Universiti Teknologi Mara (UiTM) Jasin

July 2018 - Dec 2020

- Hands on several programming language such as C++, JAVA, PHP, HTML and SQL
- Experienced on multimedia production using Adobe Photoshop and Premiere Pro
- Learnt about network using CISCO packet
- CGPA: 3.48

Bachelor of Information Systems (Hons.) Information Systems Engineering Universiti Teknologi Mara (UiTM) Jasin

April 2021 - July 2023

- Work on JAVA web programming with PostgreSQL using MVC Architecture
- Knowledge on software documentation (SRS, STD & SDD)
- Learnt database engineering using Oracle
- Experienced on mobile programming using Flutter and Dart
- Final Year Project: UiTM Jasin Student College Marketplace System using Laravel
- CGPA: 3.44

Work Experience

IT Support Intern | EDP Technology

August 2020 - October 2020

- Diagnose and service PC, laptop and printer
- Maintaining and service Windows server
- Participate in CCTV installation
- Configure network and worked on router, hub and switch installation

Junior Web Developer | Tarikemas Dot Com

August 2022 - October 2022

- Develop HR Management System using Laravel
- Participate in project planning and meeting
- Update project progress through Azure DevOps
- Control project versioning through GitLab

Work Experience

Backend Engineer Intern | Pos Malaysia Berhad

March 2023 - July 2023

- Develop backend services using **Golang** and native cloud application methodology such as **AWS S3**.
- Participate in **code reviews** and walkthroughs of technical specifications with other members of the team
- Translate business and functional requirements into technical specifications documents.
- Work with Echo Framework, PostgreSQL and MongoDB
- Build containerized application using **Docker** and **test REST APIs** using **Postman**
- Experienced with **CI/CD** pipeline and **Agile** principles.

Junior Backend Developer | Pos Malaysia Berhad

August 2023 - Present

- Develop backend services using Golang and native cloud application methodology such as AWS S3 and AWS Lambda.
- Develop and maintain documentation for backend processed and functionalities.
- Help integrate backend services with frontend applications
- Learn and adopt Golang as the primary programming language for backend development
- Work closely with the team to troubleshoot and resolve technical issues that arise during development and testing

Curricular Activities

- JomLaunch 2022 Crew
- Faculty Student Secretariat (SMF) of Faculty Science Computer and Mathematics UiTM Jasin 2022
- UiTM Jasin E-Sport Club Committee 2019
- Program Committee of Karnival ICT & Matematik UiTM Jasin 2019

Contact & Portfolio

- +601110944393
- muhammadnajmuddin1907@gmail.com
- https://github.com/mnajmuddean
- www.linkedin.com/in/mnajmuddean

References

- 1.En. Zainal Fikri Bin Zamzuri, CSP650 Supervisor. 019-6637675, zfikri@uitm.edu.my
- 2. Mr. So, Technician EDP Technology. 012-6674510
- 3. En. Rizal, Technical Lead Tarikemas Dot Com. 019-3372580, mrrizal@gmail.com
- 4. En. Faisal Adlin Bin Addenan, Senior Software Engineer Pos Malaysia Berhad. 019-2050692, faisal.addenan@pos.com.my